[Music]
[Applause]
this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at se - radio net SC radio
brings you relevant and detailed
discussions of software engineering
topics at least once a month
SC radio is brought to you by I Triple E
software magazine online at computer org
slash software this is my new hunt for
software engineering radio today I have
with me Bill Curtis who is the chief
scientist of Cass software and director
of the consortium for IT software
quality he is best known for leading the
development of CMM and people CMM at the
software engineering institute in 2007
he was elected a fellow of the I Triple
E today I will be talking with Bill
about software quality bill welcome to
the show thank you did I forget to
mention anything about you no no it's
pretty good okay we're here in wonderful
dr. Carson I think it's the first
interview we we do in a cassadine yes
it's pretty quick okay what is software
quality I need a simple definition that
kind of fits with the way people
normally think about quality if we have
a system that does what people expect it
to do and behaves in ways people expect
it behave and meets the requirements and
needs of the users but traditionally we
describe it in the way it sounds more
like the functional requirements it does
the things that users want to do and the
biggest problem is the users never state
non functional requirements they assume
you know those things because you're a
professional so they don't tell you that
you shouldn't have sequel injection
opportunities and you shouldn't have
buffer overflows and you should have
handle errors properly and all this and
if it doesn't you don't do those things
in the system behaves in ways that the
user suddenly doesn't expect it fails
people break in and steal proprietary
information the performance degrades
we'll what have you and the user expects
you know those things and so for the
system to continue to behave in ways
that meet the users need and meet the
users expectations and satisfy the
requirements you really need to have
this professional engineering knowledge
about software so you build it properly
it meets the functional requirements it
does what it's supposed to but it does
it in a way that
that continues to support proper use of
the system and proper delivery of the
service this system offers for the users
okay what are famous projects which
fails to address non function well a lot
of people right now I didn't know about
the Obamacare myth certainly in the
United States where the Obamacare system
was brought online on October 1 and
people were supposed to get on it and
order insurance because every American
was now required by law they have
insurance and people logged on and
nothing happened I mean they just sat
there and sat there waiting and waiting
and it's like Waiting for Godot in one
of what happened the system just not
what working and what we found out is
that the people who had built it really
didn't understand how you build
web-based systems and they just
downloaded it every possible thing that
a usual might in it want any you know
any point in their lives and it just
swallowed up all the bandwidth and it's
just really badly designed user
interface it's how they think the first
well they they the problem was that that
you know once they got the law passed
they had to go build it but the Obama
administration didn't want to build it
too quickly because they wanted to get
past the elections so the Republicans
couldn't use an issue and kill it
and so they started late and they kept
adding things and changing requirements
late in the development and they got
down over they had actually two weeks to
test the system and this is a massive
system that integrates no insurance
companies with with with federal
information about what you qualify for
and it was a mighty enormous system and
they had two weeks to test it so it was
a complete disaster and they could never
simulate you know thousands of people
getting on this or hundreds of thousands
people trying to get on this thing at
this at the same time and so as as
experts looked at they realized they
they're just trying to pass too much
stuff through the through the internet
and they don't need all that the users
had a basic set of things they needed
and other things if they could you know
they could call for later and in looking
at the system we actually could look at
some of the code that was the the
JavaScript and whatnot and we found a
security hole in the thing and so we we
sent a little email very quietly
privately to the people
these things that in Washington and said
you know this here's a little problem
it's known to be a security potential
security issue and you may want to fix
it and they and they didn't know we
played was next and in doing it they
added in an even larger security problem
so they basically had people that didn't
know how to build these kinds of these
kinds of interfaces and to get it fixed
the the Obama administration went back
to the folks that had build their
websites for getting donations during
the during the political campaigns who
did a pretty good job but even they
couldn't fix this one so they finally
went to Google and got Google to send so
they're absolutely top geniuses and to
come in and they finally got the thing
fixed because they were the gurus right
so that was that was that with a classic
one that everybody in the country saw
was on you the news I was on TV four
times trying to explain of what had
happened then why and what they can fix
and then all of this so it was a it was
a major embarrassment not only
nationally you know made the world news
but another one I was involved in was
was back in my days with ITT in the
early 80s when they were the world's
world's fifth largest company and half
the company was telecom and half was a
number of other businesses and if you
remember back in the early 80s and most
folks they're probably listening weren't
even born in but that's about the time
we were moving from analog systems into
digital systems everything was starting
to move over to computers and like the
processors and what have you and so ITT
just committed the entire telecom
business to micro processors to move out
of relays and into into a digital world
and so they they and they wanted one
architecture they could deliver anywhere
in the world as opposed to having
separate national units each of which
would build its own switch for its own
country we would have one generic switch
with a generic architecture that with
minor modifications we can deliver to
meet any country's particular tell the
community kitchen needs and so we
charged a head on this thing they hired
an auntie brilliant system architect
that understood these kinds of systems
and then designed one and back they had
to negotiate with a Swedish government
we heard he was declared a national
resource in Sweden or they finally got
it can use someone from from Ericsson of
course okay
and he was a brilliant guy I mean
absolutely brilliant and he had this
beautiful architecture and it basically
you know deleted took a telecom system
and broke it up into independent
components that could sit on different
ships and interact through messages and
and epic sounds like Michael said it
sounds like Michael services today yeah
there's nothing new of it in the
atmosphere is there but anyway so they
you know started building this thing but
the problem was those Radio 86 class
ships I mean they didn't have big
memories they didn't have big processors
and for the initial design it was fine
but they kept adding on more and more
stuff they wanted this to be the
ultimate telecom system they could do
everything you could ever think of you
know years into the future and so it you
know the functionality started exploding
they went from like a basic final 45 or
50 messages up to like 450 to 500
messages I mean a factor of 10 growth
and bandwidth between these things and
and the cold was growing and growing and
when they started trying to integrate
the system you could just see the cold
flow over the sides of the chip and onto
the floor and as though they they were
in trouble and they knew it and three
months before the first competition
which was going to be in Stuttgart to
win the German market because we were
competing with a number of other
companies they asked me to go to Europe
and you know because I was a measurement
guy collect some data and come back and
tell us if we can we have a system to
deliver in three months right so now I
could kind of basically spill telephony
at that point I'm gonna be able to go in
the architecture and figure out so I
went over there and I started looking
through the data and the data was amiss
I mean it was just incomplete and it
would make no sense which data
management data okay and I'll tell you
this why because there was nothing I
could find it would give me any any
progress report so I said well look at
the system integration server so nobody
knew about the state of the project yes
they actually some people knew they just
weren't telling anybody I'll tell you
more about that in a minute so basically
the what I saw was the amount of code
being poured into integration test which
is going up exponentially every
shoveling modules in the integration
test and as I lay I said well let me
just lay out what's going what's going
in and what's going
the rate and all that and there were all
these module numbers going into
integration test and they never came out
and they're all these module numbers
coming out of integration tests but they
never went in in fact there were twice
as many of them said what on earth is
going on here and then we tell my real
architecting the entire system in the
middle of integration test because they
finally realize the codes too big to fit
on the chips they now got to carve the
system up and redistribute things across
all these different chips well they lost
control of the generic architecture
completely so why did something like
this happens I mean if you see they
weren't measuring Sun they weren't
measuring the size of the load modules
they weren't measuring the size of what
they were creating after they compile
the code and so this it was just you
know which is blowing up on them and so
they and and that all the German market
required all the German authority
required was plain old telephone service
well we had all this other stuff on top
of it for every future capability you
could dream of so the older engineering
it as a gold plating the thing and the
the the fellow that ran our German unit
because earlier in the earlier years we
had national units in each country and
that unit would service that country in
Billis which for that country would not
but now the theory was we will have one
switch globally one architects that will
serve all national governments and you
can then just basically adapt that
architecture and make modifications to
meet the local the local requirements
sort of for that product line and and
just tailor it to meet you know add some
few things on take some things off or
whatever and so that was a theory of
well the theory was now blown to blow in
distress because we'd lost the control
the generic architecture and we split up
all over the place but when it came time
to deliver in Stuttgart and we rolled in
a couple of small racks of micro
processors and our competitors were
bringing in he'll these big hunks of
relays he large relay things and it was
a it was a nightmare
and they you know the system worked I
mean would the problem was we realized
you know the amount of code being dubbed
integral in the integration test was
going up exponentially in the amount of
code coming out was absolutely linear
and so it's clear a median we're
strictly limited by the number of people
that we have in the German facility
fixing defects right so basically the
senior executives of the ITC said okay
every man
woman and child in the United States who
can write chill Gosha suit guard and fix
his defects until til delivery date old
nation is the proshield was a
programming language and telecom it was
not picked oriented language kind of
like C++ I'm back there but had to
remember my for telling God yeah so so
at any rate we've mailed a lot of people
over there and they stayed there for
months fixing defects and and we you
know Bennet the system worked the day we
deliver to the thing worked it did plain
old telephone service they cut it into
live traffic and they never took it out
because it worked so well so we won the
market and that was great and we
everyone was thrilled we had big party
if not roaring drunk and then we won
another market I think you we want
Mexico and Italy and China and several
others and all the sudden we realized oh
my gosh we've lost the control of the
genetic architecture and now the cost of
modifying the system to each to meet
each set of national requirements
exceeds the profit we're out of business
and and it came down they had to win 45
percent of the American market against
the ESS number five from AT&T to even
survive and the architecture was such a
mess at this point that they could they
couldn't get it fixed in time and you
know yes it's number five locked up the
American market ninety was basically
done and sort of they sold the system
off to Alcatel well all the R&D money
was already spent now so I'll could tell
them made money on it you know because
they it was already developed they kind
of had it working but it was it was a
major problem and they weren't measuring
they weren't measuring size and we're
measuring them but other things they
weren't reporting management results
here but here's the story of the
management aspects nobody knew you new
york which is headquarters for ITT knew
what was going on they that's why they
sent me over they didn't know if they
had a system to deliver right and I
couldn't find any data that would tell
me anything and so I'm sitting in this
office that they put they any date on
Proctor yeah yeah how many how far what
kind of progress are we making and and I
found just sitting there and a wondering
what on earth is going on in this office
at the end of this hall there's not many
people in that hall and I said you know
this this data is garbage you guys will
just go look at the garbage of the trash
can
you know
I mean I was just so frustrated it was
just the dunya not so I started digging
through the trash can - I wonder what
they throw away over here lo and behold
it's the project manager report for
Europeans development centres sorry it
was the project managers report for
European development centres a report
they made sure never went to New York
because they didn't want the execs from
New York coming over and bothered them
right and this head this had the
property report it had all the progress
and how much code was going in that the
linear code coming out but you could
trust that because it was a and it has
only shared among the European managers
at the development centers it was not
real they would not allow it to go to
anyone else it was only it was their
private report so they could track it
but they wouldn't let anybody in New
York nor a headquarters or you know
European headquarters or anywhere else
and and lo and behold that's where I
figured out what was going on looking at
that and and but what the problem was
they basically in losing control of the
architecture okay they lost control of
the company they had to basically had to
sell a hotel accomplice off cut it cut
the company in half because they weren't
measuring thanks simple things like the
size of the low margins okay yeah I mean
it's it's interesting that oh it should
be clear that if you don't have quality
you you know yeah it's embarrassing
you're you're on television you're on
the memo on the front page of the New
York Times or even worse you go out of
business
well that's happen and when I talk to
people and about projects with bad
quality usually the first thing is they
say let's do more testing but obviously
I mean you can't it testing is not
enough here the short story that the
worst one more recently was night
trading in New York it's a high-speed
stock trading company on down on Wall
Street and they had they were upgrading
a system putting the new reliefs in and
all the sudden it activated a lot of
dead code the dead coach code you
thought nothing could reach and you
don't need anymore and you should take
it out of the system but they they just
left it there what the heck technical
debt right and all of a sudden this and
this new version somehow activated the
dead code and it made four hundred and
thirty million dollars of bad trades
within thirty minutes
we're bankrupt now there's 30 minutes
out of business Wow yeah that's that's a
and then you get all you almost of these
a lot in fact a lot of these these hacks
you hear about now the Heartland which
has been and in the US was sequel
injection we've known about sequel
injection since the late 90s how can
these things be in the system well we
know we really need force especially in
security and things like that we know
about certain kinds of violations and
weaknesses why don't we have the same
kind of effort we had with y2k you know
you have to get down to a system or
everything will fail well these if we
have to get these out of the system or
the hackers will take all your credit
card numbers you know then we evenly
distributed over the provinces of Russia
so so I mean what can we do or what can
these companies do the number one they
took after they got to to improve
quality yeah well nothing like things
they have to there's a number of things
they have to do it I'm gonna go back to
some other things in a minute but but
they have to look at the architecture up
front you can't refactor a bad
architecture you can throw it out and
that's the smart thing to do what you
trying to notion that it is going to
emerge and you can refactor it in the
case of large systems is just nonsense
it doesn't happen that way and we found
actually the highest quality is in
systems where the method used to develop
them was a hybrid between sort of a
traditional waterfall upfront approach
and an agile approach out back where
they're you know they're they're
building and testing and building and
testing and building and testing to get
rapid feedback on the quality of the
implementation we get the architecture
right nothing that not complete but we
know we're on the right path with it and
we're not likely to buy the farm later
and then we have the rat then we have
the rapid you know sprint
implementations where we're testing it
to know our key is the cobra building
good code does it meet the requirements
etc that seems to give the highest
structural quality yeah I heard a while
back an interview with I forgot his name
but he was he's deeply involved in the
agile community and he said yet that the
edge' community did a little disservice
to
the rest of the community by not
focusing on architecture or not enough
focusing attention because you cannot
reflect our problems and then the answer
and you get a decent you get the real
leaders in that community guys like
Scott Ambler and they're absolutely
clear you know you need a sprint zero
where in it could be of some substantial
length where you really get to a point
where you're comfortable you're on the
right track with your architecture and
then you start the rapid you know three
week four week whatever whatever
Sprint's to get the code built but but
and that works we've got hard data on
analyzing systems that shows that that's
the best approach when it went in terms
of structural quality so now what else
can you do the the whole CMM was
designed to solve a set of problems and
they were problems were killing systems
if you remember back in the 80s you know
it was never on time it was way over
budget and it half the time didn't work
when you got there or it was riddled
with defects and a lot of thought well
we just need better languages and better
tools and that's what we were working on
and one fella said no you're all wrong
that is not the problem you will not
solve anything with better language
isn't better tooled until you get
management under control and of course
that was watching Humphrey and what said
look the problem is that when executives
or project managers come up with
schedules it can't possibly be achieved
then the developers just start having to
work at breakneck pace they barely have
time to get the code written they don't
have time to evaluator to test it and so
they're just cranking out garbage and
they know it and they're frustrated
they're they they don't feel like they
can work like a professional and they
can't because you've never gave him the
time to do it right and so the the level
2 of the CMM was designed to get control
of commitments and baselines so suppose
you don't do that the quality is gonna
be terrible okay but what is CMM maybe
so there hey buddy yeah capability
maturity model was a model develop the
software engineering Institute Carnegie
Mellon to help an organization improve
their process in several stages that
continued to build you know a
world-class software development
organization but it was done it was done
in stages and the first stage was you
must stabilize the projects you can't
have organizational level dik-diks you
know you have to do everybody has to do
this it's not going to work if the
projects aren't stable you know if guys
are working
breakneck pace and not having time to
properly design or properly test the
pill so the stable project is a project
were two things it has it has
commitments that it believes it can meet
okay okay and it controls the baselines
that's control of the requirements
baseline and control of the product
baseline now it doesn't mean you can't
change to make changes but you then go
back and so it does this does this
affect schedule or the are you know our
cost or whatever and and you make
adjustments and you can add people or
you can cut functionality or you know
and whatever you need to do but you
don't want people working at the
schedule they can't achieve because
they'll never have time to do work in a
professional way and that was the first
thing we had to fix and that's a local
fix at the project levels level two is
about projects and getting people into
an environment where they can behave
like professionals they have a fighting
chance to do work in a professional way
once you once you have the project
stable then you can look and see what
practices are working best you know this
team has a great design set of design
practices those folks have some really
good testing practices over here they've
got some good estimation practices let's
integrate all this together into a
common organizational way of doing it we
can tailor it for you know big projects
and small projects and new technology
and legacy stuff and what-have-you but
the bottom line is we have a set of
practices that we know in our
environment work and work well and we
know how to tailor them to fit different
situations and then I get them I get
really get an economy of scale we have
an organizational culture to software
culture and when that happens you see us
the developers that carry it not not the
managers it's the developers they look
stop doing that but you're screwing up
you know the way we build software and
it's just gonna delay us and that's
gonna it's gonna mess up the system so
they will be the first ones to react
when somebody starts violating you know
good practices because they already know
what's going to happen when it takes
place so the developers really become to
carry the culture this is a lot of pride
and the quality of what they're
producing quality goes up dramatically
in this case that they they know what it
takes to do the work they they can make
estimates that are reasonable and know
what it takes to control of their they
know what practices work well so that's
level three and then we can you know
higher up goes into sort of statistical
management and other kinds
things in the innovation would not but
we know that just as a higher level
means better organization means a better
organization if it's done right and a
lot of people knew where to buy a
level-five not really not really achieve
it they just want to you know get the
Box checked but the people that really
go about it and really use statistics
and measures as the way they manage the
software I mean the truth is in the
measures and they use that to control
what they're doing and adjust as they
need to just quality levels that we've
seen quality improved by 100 fold in
higher maturity levels when it's done
right and when it's an end-to-end
process that's that's managed with with
data on what's going on they can adjust
much earlier and they learn what how to
tweak practices to work more effectively
and it really is it's really a much like
lean you know the lean concept exactly
you ought to ask it yeah it sounds like
it's really statistical process control
and then but it's different because this
is an intellectual artifact traditional
lean of statistical process techniques
were developed on manufacturing where
I'm doing exactly the same thing over
and over and over over hundred times now
software's not that I never do the same
thing twice and so we have to we have to
think about how do we use data in an
intellectual environment as opposed to a
physical environment because this is
intellectual artifact and in truth the
measurement of intellectual artifacts
like software or even text is in its
infancy
I mean we've tried a bunch of things and
sometimes you're working sometimes it
didn't but there's a lot we don't know
and we used to think well we just
measure the structure of a paragraph for
instance back in the 50s and that will
tell us how understandable it is and
then we found out that doesn't work
because understandable this depends
mostly on how much you know about the
topic and that's not a structure of this
right and so that's why in an
intellectual domain this doesn't behave
according to physical laws and we have
to understand measures as indicators but
not apps you know they're not absolute
like a law of physics would be exactly
so but it's but you can do it properly
in the world yeah let's go back to the
don't do it properly yeah cuz you know
that sounds all fantastic but I when I
studied CMM had this you know negative
well it doesn't mean
Heavyweight and will see my bias you
have to produce only documents yeah CMMI
is too heavyweight it wait way overdone
and it's because they lost control the
architecture the folks that built the
CMM were not involved in building seaman
I what's the difference between scene
amendments in CMMI well they wanted to
integrate systems and software number
one because the CMM was a software model
and the system engineers had their own
and they want to integrate both of those
and see CMM was what's called a staged
model it basically builds your
architecture department it builds the
organization level by level but the
model is this is how the organization
works right and there's something called
a continuous model which is not an
organizational model it's a practice
model so it says okay the practice I
care about is testing so I'm going to
take testing up to level 5 well if you
don't take design up to level 5 right
that can have and it just said just take
the practices you're interested in and
work on them and duck doesn't reflect
trying to grow an organization as an
organization so you don't see the same
culture change you see we're seeing them
see them really fundamentally transforms
the organization in a series of stages
it's stabilized standardized optimized
innovate and you're basically taking the
you know it leveled - it's about
projects it's almost a tribal but since
each project has its own way of being
stable but then out of this I have to
build a common culture and a common
process that works for our organization
and so now I'm kind of moving up to a
the level of the civilization of
city-states becoming a country in a
sentence and and in doing that you you
really get to a whole new level away the
organization functions and a great
description doesn't take the CMM
approach but a description of how
powerful this is is in Jim Collins's
books you know built to last and good
great where he talks about the RHIB the
power of really great organizations is
in their system in their process and how
they operate as a company because I have
a common way of doing it everybody
understands it and buys in and therefore
the system operates very effectively and
that's what we're trying to get to it
with CMM CMMI said those two models the
organizationally based can stage model
and
practice-based continuous model were two
representations of the same thing and
they aren't they're theoretically not
the same and they're practically not the
same but to make those kind of make them
into the same modeling they built this
architecture it was way overdone and so
CMMI got huge because they basically
didn't understand the theory and lost
control of the architecture and so there
were all these practices and they've got
very expensive to do the assessments
there was tremendous duplication of
mattresses yeah and so and so only
people just said no we will buy the book
because there's a lot of good guidance
in there but we're not worried about
doing the assessment having descended
all these practices that was unfortunate
yeah I think hopefully with the next
generation of CMMI they'll bring it back
to something that's more more
appropriate for most businesses more
lean is the issue here we want something
Slean and really only includes a
practices that you really must have
exactly so that but that means you need
to know all the back practices and you
need to understand at once I'm one for
ya open e yeah so what are companies
like Google or Netflix doing good well
they're probably they would probably
never tell you they're doing Samuel or
CMMI and they wouldn't want to but if
you went in and looked at what they're
doing they're probably doing something
very much like that yeah I mean they
don't have to say they're doing it
probably they got the greatest piece of
software bill with space shuttle
avionics it was probably the most
elegant beautiful and and high-quality
system ever created and that was the
model for what a level-five was I mean
they were incredible I visited there and
spent days down there and I had never
seen anything like it but they would
never ever claimed they were level 5 I
mean when I looked down I said look we
know we're not level 5 because there's
things we don't do but this is what we
do do and we know it works and we know
that when we deliver software to NASA we
believe there's no defects and then they
can affect safety which means basically
since nobody knows what to fix safety in
space because space is bizarre place it
basically it was very close to defect
free you couldn't prove it was defect
free and every once in a while they find
they find something but in most of stuff
that we're finding was had been a defect
enter ten years
there's a process was very good at
delivering very elegant code but but
they would never claim to be level five
but they were just rigorously doing
these practices because they know it
served their need which is basically
almost zero defects software so you know
and really a company has to decide
what's the level of quality we need if
I'm in Telecom I'm allowed a certain
amount of downtime every year and
they're not gonna pay me to go to zero
so I need to adjust my practices to get
to that level and then that's fine that
meets my business need so that's you
know that's really the critical issue
here and we do see and there's a lot of
data now that the higher the maturity if
you're really doing it to improve the
way you build software defect rates go
down dramatically productivity goes up
people start being able to reuse stuff
because they trust it now they didn't do
that before so there's all kinds of
advantages that we see when it's done
right but I don't okay so I don't want
any don't want to have to certification
for CMMI level five or thoughts you know
I should look what look at that see if
it makes your needs yeah if it makes
anybody know we know that people who
really can implement a serious program
like that have lower defect rates and it
costs less to build software good data
out that says they're building it for
fewer dollars for a function pointer per
line of code or every favorite measure
is because they're not wasting time in a
low maturity organization 40% of the
effort is spent on fixing mistakes in
the lean world that's muda right it's
waste and and that you know and what you
want to do is eliminate the amount of
waste you have wasted time you have
fixing mistakes you want to catch them
early and get them out of the system so
it's not spinning you know ten times
more everything so on the back is
undoing stuff and rebuilding stuff and
really grating stuff and all in
especially Aki takes work and you're
dead meat critical part of the
architecture yet better software East is
the premier industry event for software
professionals covering the entire
application lifecycle
Elden Orlando Florida there's November
13th through 18th better software East
offers deep dive
topics including leadership project
management mobile development software
design and role as an added bonus the
event is co-located with the agile dev
and DevOps East conferences and one
registration automatically gives you
access to all three programs to build a
customized week learning that fits you
in your organization's specific needs
explore the program at BSC East tech
well comm su radio listeners receive up
to $600 off with code SE Radio when they
register by the September 16th super
early bird deadline in BSC East Tech
well calm yeah but yeah I think it's
interesting that whatever methods you
invent you know even if you get oh the
first thing you read this you don't have
to apply everything you know just take
the stuff which makes sense for you well
I wouldn't ignore that and just but
here's the thing here's a problem most
people believe that before we had CMM
but they weren't doing they weren't they
weren't doing the right stuff they were
believing all I have to do have better
design practices and better testing
practices and better tools and they left
man they didn't touch management because
they were thinking about engineering and
they weren't thinking about the fact
that we're doing a crummy job in
engineering because we don't have the
time to do it right and until somebody
said no the first step is you must get
control of management you must control
your commitments you must control your
baselines right and so you need guidance
and that's what CMM provided was saying
look these are the important elements
you must have to solve this set of
problems and once that solved then
here's the next set of problems and so
it organized an approach to solving
problems and it didn't it didn't let you
leave out some of the critical parts it
was just one no fan of the continuous
model because it lets you leave out
critical parts I can focus on
engineering and not focus on management
and I'm back to schedules I can't
achieve so now you say there is a
relation between CMM and lean some for
me it was always like CMM and Adria and
Berry
their identity but it should be but but
the problem is the way seem a mile
worked in the assessment method work you
had that you had to have evidence you
performed every single practice that
wasn't true and CMM you had to achieve
the goals and see them and we want to
say have you achieved the goals these
practices or guidelines for what you
might do to achieve those goals but if
you've got a better way to do it or you
don't have to do all the time and you
achieve the objectives of the goals then
fine but see them I said every practice
has to be yesterday right and that's
auntie lien because lien would say it
may be a good practice but if it doesn't
add value then they don't do it and and
so the scampi method kind of that's
where we got this butting heads with
with the lean concepts okay okay you
mentioned two continuous smaller so that
is continuous delivery therefore sis no
no not at all continuous uses I can pick
any practice design practice and take it
up and down the levels I can go if I
long hey I want to be level five and
design but I'm only going to be stay at
level two and management okay and so it
just says it's practice based everything
is this practice in that practice but
it's not the organization and the
essence of the CMM is we really
conceived at the stage model it's an
organizational transformation and I'm
using the and I'm integrating this these
collection of processes to fundamentally
change the way the organization works
it's not about design or about planning
it's about getting a management
infrastructure in place that doesn't
make bad commitments and it's able to
control the baselines and control chains
so it doesn't throw you into chaos right
and then it's about getting things
organized in a way I have a common way
of doing it that I can tailor to
different projects but it's the
organization's way of doing it's not I
just have a good design technique around
with it testing
okay so that's now and so I'm not a fan
personally of the continuous model a lot
of people are I'm not but if I were
going to reorder tech these things I
would split them because they need
putting them together the architecture
you have to have just makes it a lot of
duplication a lot of a lot of excess it
doesn't need to be there so if you want
a continuous model have it but don't try
to force stage to fit with that in a
common way
because what happened is they wait they
took the stage model and way overburden
it with practices there was duplication
it was just it was since I would really
I would break them apart and and there's
some you know additions and changes but
it the basics are there is not it's not
in a bad situation but I would certainly
break them apart and change the
architecture to reduce the duplication I
mean they basically made a matrix
there's this set of practices and
resists other practices you know ones on
the road ones on the column you have to
fill in every every every cell no good
designer works that way everybody builds
a matrix
mmm fills in all the cells and then says
which cell is important right and if
it's not it's not as ill it's important
what's on the metrics now well they have
specific for they call specific
practices on on one axis and those are
the unique practices you would perform
for management or design or testing or
whatever then they have practices on the
other axis which they call generic
practices and those have to be applied
to every single process area okay in
order to institutionalize it but so one
of those is configuration control well
I've got a process area called
configuration control so now I'm sitting
are saying they have configuration
control on my configuration control and
when they got to level 4 it blew up I'm
gonna have statistical process control
of my statistical process control that
didn't make any sense
so I mean the theory blew up in it but
they didn't do anything about it and and
so I'll just get rid of the generics and
and because I can I know how to build
all of that stuff into the basic model
so you don't have redundancy and it
doesn't it doesn't increase it that much
but it cuts the model by at least 40
percent in almost 50 percent in some
cases in practices and makes it much
more much more conformant with the
original tent that Watts had and the
90 min ahead when we built the CML okay
so now if the u.s. digital government
would ask you to design you know a new
maturity model in times of DevOps and
continuous delivery
well yeah you add those practices in
right I mean a level two is about
getting the project stable so I don't
want the DevOps operation if that's my
gonna be my process do at least be
properly estimated and you know and we
we understand what we're gonna get done
by wind so we can track early on are we
making progress or we're not making
progress at the right rate and if we're
not making progress we're falling behind
we need to take corrective action I mean
doesn't guarantee you're gonna you're
gonna have your estimates are gonna be
right but it does guarantee you'll know
they weren't so that you can take some
corrective that maybe you cut
functionality maybe you extend the
schedule or whatever but you don't say
I'm the deliverer all volunteer on
October 1 it only tests it for two weeks
that you see what's that with one
project and then you move on than that
you can't eat yeah and you move it out
across the organization project by
project it's not I don't have to have
the project won't finish before but I
get these guys working on it then I get
the next guys and I get the next and
what we found is the best way to do
that's called project launch workshops
so upfront at the at the very beginning
of the project and you have a Peter
consultants or whoever the experts are
their internal it's fine work with the
project to build a plan to understand
you know do we have the requirements
pretty well set or a lot of things that
have been stated we need to go back and
ask them about so let's make sure we
understand what we're trying to do or
we've got good stories or whatever and
then and then we we've got an estimate
for how much work we can get done by
such and such a date if it's date
constrained if not then we look at what
we have to build and say by when can we
get this done and you just basically
have a plan that you can track and and
if you're wrong that's okay but you'll
learn from it as long as you're tracking
you'll realize we weigh or underestimate
the amount of time it would take to do
this next time you know we make that
adjustment but we now we need to make a
change in our plan you deliver less
functionality your extended schedule or
whatever but is it hard to convince
companies to try that out I mean that I
see I see not after a disaster
okay but but that's the problem let me
tell you here's how you do it let me
tell you one thing I mean I am a
consultant and I just won that if I have
to wait until a big disaster runs you
have to wait until the executive wants
to make improvements
if the executives don't back it it's not
gonna work I mean you have to have
executive management to support to make
the process improvement program work and
once you've got that you're on your way
cuz they'll say we are going to do these
things and managers that don't want to
do these things will no longer be
managers not they have to be willing to
remove these managers who won't go on
and the successful ones do and you see
you see some people you know continue on
as managers because they understood what
management was and other guys who just
wanted to have a good time into doing
something else so that's that's critical
and then let's see if there was a was
the other part of your question when you
get you have to have management support
you roll it out you roll it out in
project by project so these projects
workshops really and then whoever the
consultant just comes back periodically
and and sort of how are you doing or you
have any issues except for cetera so you
don't have to have a disaster you just
have to have an executive say we we need
to get this under control and I'll tell
you the way I've convinced them of the
value of it is you know what you're
talking about process their eyes will
glaze you ask them one simple question
how many good project managers do you
have you know you know and then you
start counting their fingers and realize
I don't even need one hand to count the
good you know if they're a little
maturity organization they centralized
they they don't really have good
managers in place and these guys aren't
trained they probably never they were
just promoted because they were good
coders and you since they look and you
start this program the first thing I'm
going to give you it's project
management these people will learn what
it means to manage project plan projects
to track projects to make take
corrective actions to work with their
people and what you will come out with
is project managers who can deliver
projects ultimately they'll learn what
it takes to do good estimating deliver
them on time but that's then a sudden
it's okay yeah I get that because
they're man if they're executives they
have been six hopefully they've been
successful at management and they
understand what they're not saying and
they need to see and that helps them
that really helps them convince
themselves they need to launch this and
then force it
it's probably not easy I mean if you're
not even if you're convinced you need a
better project management you know where
to find this guy well you're gonna say
you're gonna have to train them you're
gonna have to find people with an
orientation torreón it's not always the
best programmers that have an
orientation towards being managers so so
that's part of it so they'll be trained
and they'll and that's what the launch
workshops do you work with the the
putative manager to learn what it means
to manage yeah they'd learn how to build
a plan they learn how to evaluate
requirements to make sure you know they
know what's what's complete what's
incomplete and what they need to go back
and ask about they learned that they
need to get some plan for configuration
management how we're going to control
the configurations of this thing and the
versions and all that until you get that
in place often the resistance
there's early resistance from the
developers because you're gonna put me
in a straightjacket and make me much
like a robot or something and the thing
to explain the developers listen you're
already gonna you're already in a
straightjacket and you are marching like
not like a robot but like a crazy rabbit
because you got scheduled you can't
achieve right and they say yeah and they
say you know how much time do you have
to sit down and really think through
your design issues none I just got to
get code out right and so they suddenly
realize if you can get control of this I
can act more like a professional it's
not about me to adhere to some idiotic
process it's basically free me up to
engage in professional practice and
follow a process that we know or we're
talking in grad school would actually
work probably it's also about you know
creating some awareness of these games
because what we see is architecture you
know the lore filha don't think about
architecture but if you do a workshop
and say you know there you have to you
have to look at that you have to get you
know you have to think about all the ill
ETS and things like that and so yeah and
so here's the other the other issues is
that the the next body resistance comes
from middle management if you're in a
big organization because they've gotten
to where they got they're not project
managers now they're higher up and
they've gotten to where they are about
whatever it is they were doing they knew
how to manage
relationships and push guys to work
nights and weekends and bring in
carryout pizza and all that I mean now
their whole way of existing is
threatened right I mean they can't they
can't kind of use these motivational
techniques in one day and they sometimes
feel like this is an invasion of their
private domain and the way they want to
run they're like what is it threatened
because their things are gonna change
below them and there's an executive
above who's putting pressure on them and
they don't really have complete control
over what's going on below them although
they'll have a lot more control if they
get good management in place but a lot
of them just have had a way to run their
business that was you know I just dive
beyond me I gotta make these commitments
and I motivate people to meet them you
know and there are up here nights in the
weekend but you can't do that anymore
how does it work and let's let's stick
to the Google example most people think
that googling I can't I am NOT why I
can't tell you how Google works
internally because I've not been inside
Google I do know this and several things
go on number one they have a common code
tree so they're all working against this
this common code tree they hire really
against what the common code tree I mean
it's where although they offered a they
have one the auditory yeah and everybody
works against it they they do buy some
commercial tools from what we've heard
but they chronically built a lot of
their own tools because they're way
beyond what commercial tools can do and
their requirements for the tooling is
just out there I mean the future of
software engineering is being is being
developed in companies like Google and
Amazon and in Microsoft what not because
they're they really are at a level of
usage you know how many billions of
people sign onto Google and Amazon and
MSN and all this and so they have they
have stresses that nobody else has yet
but a lot of people will have and so
they're having to develop the tools to
manage the way they go about this
they're having to build process these
where they can update systems in flight
you know how do you repair an airplane
who quits 35,000 feet in the air will
they kind of learn to do that with
software while while they're in
operation and there's specific things
they do and they have rule
with it so there are processes that they
have to pretty rigorously follow to be
able to do the things they're doing at
the scale they're doing it and under the
kind of performance pressure they're
doing it implements pressure but one is
pressure in an innovation well no
performance pressure and sense of when I
get on Google I want to answer when I
get on the Amazon I want to I want to
see it out of thryce yeah and I don't
want to wait five minutes you know I'll
go have a cup of coffee come back and
see if they've figured out what it will
come a question one so they have that
kind of performance demand which is
extraordinary right and they've got
these huge server forums and everything
else to help manage that demand but that
itself is a body of infrastructure
software there's really quite something
and so that and they have to innovate
because everybody's competing again you
know competing against each other who
you know therefore those three are
competing to see who's going to be it's
going to own the the cloud and everybody
wants to now have to be you you you have
them you use them as the cloud service
and so there's high competition in there
there I really do have to innovate but
at the same time they can't lose control
of what they've got because we expect it
to perform twenty six seven 365 and you
know it almost microsecond speeds so
they that requires that you really do
have a very rigorous internal they could
care less about size things I've seen
them but they if we went in there we
probably find an awful lot of the
practices they put in place wouldn't
meet the requirements because they have
to perform at that level and they they
use measurements a lot yeah I think
that's really interesting I mean that's
for me the the bridge to you know
software process improvement and things
like that that Google I don't know but
Spotify they measure basically there is
everything there is a measure for
everything they don't do anything in
they don't put anything a little bit
further if they don't have the data that
prove that you know a little thing works
and yeah
absolutely and you know the whole
concept the Lean Startup is get data on
one works and what people want and then
go down that path you know cut off this
path that they didn't care about so that
so there's you know they really do have
to be constantly innovating just to
compete with the other guys that are
constantly innovating is AHA maturity
you know level five about constant
innovation having a standard process you
can bring that back into an update and
then you know learn what the new
measures are you'll have what exactly
thresholds and baselines and all that
are so this is you know it's pretty
sophisticated stuff and the maturity
model gives you a good guide for how to
get there
and doing it because you want the
certification is not the reason do it
because you want to compete like the
dickens I mean you really want to get
that where you're able to innovate
you're able to compete at a very high
level you're not wasting a lot of time
on fixing defects and trying to read
refactor architectures that you
shouldn't have to refactor and that's
our next thing so that's that's the
objective with the processes snowball of
laws disease and I and one thing I'd
recommend people look at is watch
Humphreys team software process because
the data on that is extraordinary it
basically says as a developer I want to
develop myself the way an athlete would
develop them you know athletes
everything's measurement I'm gonna
measure everything they do and so what
what said is you know if people would
just measure how they make mistakes how
long it takes to do things you know
their own personal process and then the
ants they get together in a team they
can say this is what I can do this is
what I can and the team makes better
commitments and they start learning at a
much faster rate they learn why they
make mistakes so they avoid that in the
future the data on the team software
process is absolutely extraordinary in
terms of quality levels and productivity
levels I can imagine I mean I only read
the book on the person software process
it was already pretty interesting
because they they said stuff like okay
please please check out how you work you
know yeah how if you go to the toilet
make a note if some well yeah if
somebody asked you something
make a note but what it showed to me was
I rarely work more than 20 minutes
concentrated on something
and then it's like okay once you have
the others not everybody knows the
extent that watch does watch was a
unique individual what's what's ahead
statistical process control over how he
balanced his checkbook
he literally measured how long it took
how he mistakes he made how long it took
to fix him and he got the way he never
made mistakes balancing his checkbook
you do exactly how many pennies he had
every I mean he was an extraordinary
individual not everybody has to get to
that level but if you want to be a truly
great software engineer you need to know
what you're able to do so you can spot
the weaknesses in your own personal way
of doing software development and
correct it and learn why you make
certain kind of mistakes and correct
that and as a team I mean I know that
Spotify they and that they have the
squats and they have all kinds of
measures on their on their squats which
means and measures on everything like
what is the value the customer value
they produce but never sourcing what
what's the preach to to the see any
software the team is I and even I needed
all my data before I can tell you and
integrate with your data I need to know
how I perform before I can tell before I
can tell you how I what I can do what I
can't do and how we coordinate if I come
into the team launch meeting and we're
trying to figure how much can we get
done and in a reasonable amount of time
what our commitments we each have to be
reasonable about what we can get done
because traditionally you know the smart
guy in the room would say well I'll do
that oh yeah I'll do that and I'll do
that and I'll do that and they would get
grossly overloaded and they would become
a bottleneck and the team would slow
down because nobody else could get stuff
done cuz a weakness has got to finish
stuff and it becomes a mess and so what
this is that each person needs to know
what they can reasonably expect to get
done in a reasonable length of time
without working nights and weekends and
all that and not overload themselves but
but spread the work across the team so
the team can perform at a at a
sustainable level and and and know and
and make commitments that they believe
they can meet and then they can learn
why they didn't meet them right if I've
got the data I know okay overestimate
the disk because I forgot I had to do
this
little thing and and so it becomes much
more much more disciplined and so when I
when I moved when I had my first extreme
programming and scrum project yes
exactly these things happened so you
know basically they strum follows just
practices scrum it strong him done
properly he's very powerful
what is from them well I remember the
same Sutherland even when the developers
are scrum at a whether agile and large
conferences he still have been they've
given a sort of a long session he middle
of a said you know seventy percent of
the companies I visit are doing scrum
but what we're doing scrum but we don't
whole daily stand-ups but we don't do
daily bills but we don't know they're
not doing scrum all right they're doing
scrum but says that so they're they're
not they're not truly agile they're not
doing the method it's just undisciplined
hacking and and and too much of what was
called agile people just use that as an
excuse to kind of do what they wanted to
do
whereas scrum is a disciplined method
and if you do it properly you'll get
very good results and and you know
number the other agile methods are that
way the various crystal methods that I
was Alistair and it's the Kobayashi
Copeland developed he his concept was
you can't apply the same method to every
type of project you know the huge
projects gonna be different because you
got team multiple teams and all so he
adjusted the practices in each level of
a method to work with the kind of
organization the kind of challenge
you're facing in that kind of project in
turn he adjusted it you know he tailored
the process to fit the nature of the
project that very good very good sense
in that there was a lot of good thinking
by some of the top guys that went in to
the thinking about what a truly agile
program is the one thing they threw out
that was in many cases that was a very
powerful practice when the data is
absolutely clear on this is one of the
best practices in software engineering
with formal inspections it is remarkable
its ability to capture and remove you
know defects very early and they they
venting convictions and sends off
Pepperell creme encoder program is their
programming is not formal inspections
formal inspections is you know I've
built my component or I've designed
I component I want two or three other
people to review it and that means by
fall inspecting me they will go off and
spend time to review it and it will have
an inspection meeting where they'll come
back and so these are the things we
found right and so I may have one guy
looking for security problems and one
guy looking for functional problems and
you know so different people take
different perspectives to make sure and
it was incredibly powerful that's gone
because it you can't you know you can't
that's not gonna work nestling these
three week cycles what are you you and
the three the three week cycles you'd
have on a scrum or four-week cycle in a
sprint a single sprint right and so one
of the things that can replace that if
it's done well as structural analysis is
static analysis and maybe some dynamic
analysis because if you can if you can
really do analysis on the system as
built you know not just decoding units
with with ninety etool but really look
at integration time and integrate the
software and then run aesthetic and now
at the system level you know you found
it yet the code level you found cold
problems of the system over you found
system problems and many of these are
the same problems you would have found
in a formal inspection so if you can use
more the advanced tools that are out
there now for static analysis dynamic
analysis behavioral emulation some of
these other things you'll gain back some
of the power that was lost when form
inspection for joining so there are
things that can make that can make agile
very powerful and because you do have
much faster feedback which is critical
and if teams have time to take the
feedback and absorb it and then make
their decisions about what they're going
to do about it you know that what's
wrong with the system they learn they
learn about parts of the system that you
didn't know about before they learn
about assumptions they had that weren't
correct you may learn about certain kind
of structural issues that were that
weren't efficient and and that just
makes them a much more powerful team but
usually I should always do some sort of
inspection I mean I could imagine when I
collect the requirements then somebody
should it be really good sure but it
would be a really good idea to have some
kind of formal inspection to make sure
you know what what are these complete if
some of them been left so fuzzy that we
really don't know what it is and the
same thing with stories are not
necessarily requirements or like
requirements but they're not exactly
right and so if I'm gonna live off
stories I need to I need them to
understand what assumptions are being
made that aren't being stated you know
what are the aspects of this system that
you're not going to get by by reading a
story by getting a scenario and and and
that needs to be thought out so that you
you don't go down the wrong path with
the architecture or whatever exactly
yeah but my problem with with
inspections my problem with inspection
is it's already too late you know when I
have to do a larger review I'm like Oh
God so many details I just don't know
anything about it lots of things get
lost so I'm just wondering if it's you
know a healthy back and forth or it is
if it's done on a rigorous I mean in a
well-run waterfall the agile world is
always react against the waterfall
things a bunch of garbage the finest
software ever built was built with the
software especially on their software
the best stuff ever built well there's a
rigorous space shuttle avionics system
and you're probably the prettiest piece
of software ever it was built with a
rigorous top-down why would say top-down
was built with a rigorous waterfall
model I mean hold on hold on most people
aren't doing a waterfall with any
discipline or rigor if they just get
some idiotic date thrown at them and say
go build it and and there's really not
the discipline retire it wasn't the
waterfall it would it was the bad
management and the poor discipline that
led to a mess and they said look if we
could at least get faster feedback
because number one the customer doesn't
know what they want and so I really need
to be able to give them a piece of the
system prototype if you will get them to
react to it and then and then I'll build
it if they like it then we can build a
next piece on top of that but I want to
give them something that they that works
that they can look at they can they can
decide okay what do you want next what
storage makes sense to you and so
there's you know there was that aspect
and the ruler and the Space Shuttle was
okay we build prototypes all the time
they build NASA wasn't sure about the
requirements we build a prototype that
react to it but the rule was we throw
out the prototype because it was not
built with a level 5 process and it
probably contains defects we don't even
understand the products are just very
even eyeing us to get the requirements
straight to get too close okay not a
problem
requirements traits or also requirements
and you know proto
to prove non-functional yeah well but
you probably wouldn't put the
non-functional prototype there you
wouldn't prove the non-functional
necessarily the prototype unless you
were aimed at trying to figure that a
certain structural probably not right
because you're not building it to be
structurally strong you're building it
to demonstrate functionality to get the
user to react one of the problems we've
got that I think we've I've seen with
with with agile is that you know the
goal is I want to respond to the
customer I want to be agile so as they
learn more about what they want in their
system you know I can I have the ability
then to change directions and get it
more to what the customer really wants
well the problem that's what if the
customer doesn't you know if we assume
they don't always know what they want
but here's the worst case the worst case
is going to a bank how do banks grow
they grow by buying other banks right
and each bank has its own process and
its own way of doing things and they
don't want to change and so if my
representative the agile team is you and
you're from division a you don't care
what division B wants and division B is
not gonna want necessarily all the
things you want it and so I'm just
getting your view but there maybe if
I've got 20 different banks they've been
acquired they all want a different way
of doing it now all of a sudden the
requirements getting massively complex
some of them conflict and so I can't
constantly respond to whatever user
tells me and so I've got I've got to be
able to do all this stuff because that's
what the users are requiring it's some
case somebody has to put adults and
provision on the business they folks
we've got to have a common business
process here because the IT systems
we're gonna create are gonna be
monstrosity and they're gonna be
impossible to maintain and we will not
be one bank will continue to be thirty
different banks there's no economy of
scale and we'll never get the our last
somebody but most this person it doesn't
show up right exactly so the bottom line
is part of what agile needs to do it's
one that when they really do start
getting a lot of stories from different
people that are conflicting and then it
just clears a lot of different processes
out there you say look you need to go
straighten out your business process and
getting some consistency here or else
we're gonna build a monstrosity we can't
continue to respond to you if you're
telling this 87 things we actually did
an analysis in the bank one time and
every brilliant guy famous computer
scientist do it
and they had a hundred and eighty-three
processes for their credit-card division
and like they had 18 different ways to
open an account one for every different
credit card company that they serviced
right and by the time he was finding he
only spent two months need cut it down
to fifty three processes and three ways
to open an account but you just went
through and said these are you know
there's there's a lot you know everybody
had a little bit different but basically
here's the generics and you know get
down to these basics and then you have
some more small variants on it but in it
just cut their process down too much
much simpler made it much more
understandable to people that had to do
the work and the IT system then it could
be much much simpler so that leads me to
one question I I discovered these days
here was that 20% of the defects come
from bad code or something and 80 come
from bad requirements so know that
number varies based on which study you
look at but there's a large number of
problems that come out of bed
requirement you know our storms weren't
stated completely or were fuzzy and
whatnot but llores it's a lot of that
they just didn't state a requirement and
then there was a defect but there was
there was what was called a defect or
something unwanted okay no it's not a
Buckeye clicking requirements you know
the one person said this another person
said that and they weren't the same it
was never worked out and so now the
system's got this this problem how do I
fix you you get them to sit down and
work it out until they come to an
agreement on what has to be the way the
system works
and that's so if you can you you should
make that decision as an IT person or
developer it's not yet not your it's not
your responsibility it's theirs and
we've got to stop taking the blame in
software development for problems of
business has in getting their business
straight and getting their business
process simplified and organized and not
trying to have 87 different ways to do
everything and then expect us to build
that into a clean easy to maintain IT
system it's just not gonna happen
so that's icky when I discover when you
drop that money go back to the customer
to go back to the coach and say look
here's a problem I can build yeah I can
add these 87 features but it seems to me
there's only a basic set of 20 here and
this will be massively complex okay for
you and me if we don't if we don't
aren't here you said this and you said
that and that Lisa just completely
different algorithms or something but
from a contracts point of view I mean
I've been in this in this situation
quite often where I said hey look you
know this makes all no sense and then
you know the answer was like okay but
you know we we had we have fixed
requirements just do it and when you're
done we make new requirements to build
it out and that is really frustrating
really frustrating and you talk about
what you just if the customer says
that's it these are the requirements I
don't argue anymore about it you got two
choices you will build it exactly as the
customer stated deliver it exactly what
the customer said the requirements and
then negotiate all the change requests
for which will make a small fortune the
other option if you're true level 5 and
it's a real disaster and you can see
this isn't gonna work it's gonna be a
nightmare
they'll be mad and you know a year and a
half just say gentlemen we want you to
go to one of our competitors and see see
what they'll say yeah we're happy let's
you this business go to a competitor and
you get back away from it because if
you're if you're a true high maturity
organization you not have to worry about
business because people want you because
you're reliable and you're you're let
you're less expensive and you can you
can walk away from contracts you know
we're going to be disasters if I was a
had been a manager that you know the
people that Obama Claire came to be
claimed to be level five clearly they
weren't but if I want a manager and a
level five over to walk within the
contract say if you if you are not you
will not have started by this time we
will back away because we you can't you
can't test this thing we cannot
guarantee it's gonna work with two weeks
at the end of the process to test to
test this massive system it's just you
know you need to find someone who thinks
they can do that we know we can't and
and you know and if you're a high
maturity organization have a tremendous
power to negotiate because you have a
record of having succeeded and delivered
on time on schedule high quality systems
and we know we know we're the
professionals we know what it takes and
you know if you want to do it in half
the
be my guest but not us yeah I wonder I
mean I know these days I only work for a
small and medium-sized communist because
with it you know the leaders are mostly
also the owners of the company and they
really care so if you explain that to
them you know everything we did you
always forgot stuff we did not then
they're like okay there is one person
above everything which is responsible
and once that everything will be good so
I can go to these pieces
so here's but if I go to a large you
know 50,000 people company it somehow
yeah well unless they're if they're
immature yes if they're immature yes
it's a mature
much more mature not necessarily but the
biggest pom you got in a small company
especially small real small company is
that especially if they put out an IPO
right they they have public ownership or
they've got money from venture
capitalist how many of those CEOs
actually last more than three years or
even two years the problem is they know
how to get something started but they
don't know how to get it to the next
level of development they don't know the
processes and disciplines and all these
things and so you see you see these guys
get the thing started as a massive
success but they don't know how to take
it to the next level they don't know how
to scale it because they've never had to
manage in that and so they take that
that founder out and put more
experienced manager in that happens all
the time that's exactly what happens in
process improvement you find middle
managers and project managers it really
just can't move in this direction they
just can't bring you the discipline
required and you can't scale the
business without it
now the fundamental lesson and good to
great and built to last which you you
have to have a disciplined process in
order to able to scale it the the Toyota
Production method right the COG the
quality system and the Linda the
concepts in which linking start out with
the premise you have a standard process
if you don't we can't improve and sign
on second days if I just went to every
little thing everybody said then you're
then you're in you're nowhere yeah it's
like you know I I heard that from what's
the David Henderson the geography
he got asked for you know introduced
you're introduced Kanban to my
organization he was like I can't I mean
if you don't have a process already I
cannot do that yeah you know if you have
a process I can come with my Kanban and
then we can improve the way you were
sadly if everything is still a chaos we
first can tree and use one of the
fundamental concepts in Kanban is it's a
way to manage the amount of work you're
taking on because you know you you can't
add it in if there's not a slot for it
but it control it is a it is a
disciplined way to control commitments
and to learn how much you can actually
get done because you got lots of
blocking things if you're kind of
screwing around so it's a it's a very
good it's a good process we're looking
at okay I see we we already have more
than one hour so just to wrap it up so
important for software quality is you
must measure you must measure you must
control commitments you must control the
baselines and your managers have to back
the developers they really have to
provide an environment in which
developers can work in a professional
way because they were they want the
developers really want to produce
excellent stuff they're proud of their
work and if they're thrown into an
environment where they can't work in a
professional way but they've got
commitments they can't possibly meet
without being nights and weekends and
all this eventually they'll get fed up
and leave and and so controlling
commitments and baselines measuring it's
critical automate the organizational
level getting to an organizational way
of doing it and a cultural build around
that and and it'll be it'll be quite
something and then then the defect rates
go way down and it becomes much much
cheaper to produce software you're
getting stuff out much faster and the
business because that's better software
the business becomes more agile why
because you can you can make changes
much more quickly the the the business
agility is strictly limited by the
quality of the code because if it's hard
as heck to make changes that the
business needs to compete they're gonna
be behind their competitors so measure
have a discipline put discipline in
place management's responsible for
providing that environment so professed
so that the developers can use a
profession
process okay and so for architecture get
the architecture straight or you will
pay a huge price and that price may be
death yeah you cannot you cannot put you
can't refactor it for a cruddy
architectural on an important system in
the end it's impossible to put say gets
yeah and what you can do is just stop
and and typically start over okay
ripping burn good thank you bill thank
you for being on the show my bliss is
venue on for software engineering right
[Music]
thanks for listening to SC radio an
educational program brought to you by I
Triple E software magazine for more
information about the podcast including
other episodes visit our website at se -
radio - to provide feedback you can
write comments on each episode on the
website or write a review on iTunes
mention a message us on Twitter at se
radio or search for the software
engineering radio group on LinkedIn
Google+ or Facebook you can also email
us at team at se - radio net this and
all other episodes of SU radio is
licensed under the creative commons
two-point-five license thanks again for
your support
[Applause]
[Music]
you